Hey guys and welcome to the first episode of Beginners
Guide to the World of Tanks.
Done by me, HighFlyer15
Lets load up the game and go through everything the game has to offer.
As you get into the game the first thing you'll be met by is a training tutorial.
It's not really a tutorial
at all, since all it does is throw you into your first battle without knowing anything about the game.
You can either take the tutorial and receive a M3 Stuart and a few credits for your trouble, but the M3
Stuart isn't THAT good and the credits you'll get from the training will all be used to do forced stuff.
Like use all your xp on upgrading all modules on a tank, you don't really want to fully
upgrade, but the first tanks are easily upgraded, so go right ahead and take the tutorial.
And you can like me stop the tutorial at "Mission 7 out of 8", since
the only thing that'll get you past
that mission is if you buy a tier 3
tank and there's plenty for you to learn inbetween getting that far.
When you've done that get back to the video.
Even if you didn't take the tutorial, you can still
follow the tutorial
from now on, so lets get going.
At the bottom you can see your selection of tanks.
Right now you have your 4
default tanks.
These are free to buy later on, since these are the starting tanks.
You can't get any credits for selling them either, unless
you equip them with modules, which will cost credits.
As you progress in the game you'll unlock more and more tanks and the slots at the bottom
will have to be increased to house them all.
You can increase your garage by doing two things.
Either get a tank that's going to be moved in the future, not something we'll talk about any time soon or by purchasing
garage slots with gold. Gold is the real life money currency in the game and gold can be used for several things.
We'll get into that later. At the left side of the
bottom you can choose different nations, tank class and tier.
On the right side of the screen you'll see all the stats for the selected tank.
The only things that
will change here is the amount of HP you have and the rate of fire and penetration.
Also engine power.
As you equip a new turret your HP will increase a little and when
you equip a new gun, then the penetration and damage values will change aswell.
But the stats will not change, if you add equipment to your tank. For instance, if you
add a Gun Rammer to increase your rate of fire, it won't show in the stats.
Which is a little misleading, since you won't see anything change,
before you go into
an actual battle. It only changes, when you add a new module.
Lets take a look at the first 4 tanks.
The Loltractor, the MS-1, the Renault FT and the T1 Cunningham.
As you can see you've got all four standard tier 1 tank available to you from the beginning.
Earlier in
the development it was only 3, so you've gained a starting slot, since the arrival of new tanks.
Slots are worth 300 gold, 150 on sale, so
getting a new free one is
good thing.
Before anything else you're going to have to make a choice. Or choices.
You're going to have to decide which class you'll want
to aim for.
Light, medium, heavy, tank destroyer or artillery.
I'll give a quick rundown of what each tank will and will not be able to do for you
on the battlefield, before we get into the deeper end of the tech trees, speaking about specific tanks.
First up, the light tank.
The fastest of all the classes at the earlier tiers. You'll be able to fly around the battlefield, flank
and attack from behind.
You'll have close to no armor and you won't be able to deal a whole lot of damage either.
Think of the light tanks as the mosquito in the animal
world of World of Tanks.
Fast and deadly if used correctly.
Next up we have the medium tank. Slower in acceleration, more health points and bigger
guns make this class perfect for brawling in cities and with their heavier counterparts.
You'll easily be able to take on heavy tanks and win in certain 1v1 situations, but your health points will still be a lot lower,
so
you'll need to land a lot more hits than they need on you.
The medium tanks are the hyenas in the animal world of WoT.
Then we get to the big boys. The heavy tanks.
These tanks are very slow and will not get you to the party
fast.
Luckily they make up for this by having a lot more armor, health points and a lot more powerful guns.
You will have to decide very early in the match if you want to attempt flanking later or if you want to go and hold on spot
on the map. Most of the time you won't be able to do both.
Unless you're on a great team, that allows you to do so.
The heavy tanks are the lions on the battle field, since they dominate most of what's on
their path, but even the lion fear the hyena, just like in the real world.
Then we have the tank destroyers. Very fragile, most of the time very fast and
they wield VERY powerful guns most of the time. Except a few ones.
I don't really know what to call these in the animal world, since they're
mostly good at dealing damage once and then disappearing until they've reloaded.
And then we get to the artillery. Long range fighters, who can sit in one end of the map and fire
at shell all the way across the map, destroying the most heavy tank in one shell, if they're lucky.
Most of the time these are slow moving, but some of them are fast as well,
so lets describe them as monkeys. Monkeys who throw poo at the other animals.
Because that's what people think of them in the game. Everybody hates them, since they can easily ruin your
day by hitting you ONCE.
And so would getting hit by poo. Your whole day would be ruined.
Now that you know what each class is like, it's time for you to
decide. Have you decided yet? No? Well I know how you feel.
There's 4 nations to pick from, so lets go over each of them as well, which
will give you an even better idea of which way you'll want to go.
Before going into a deeper detailed view on each of the
nations tanks, lets just describe them with a few words.
USSR. Sloped tanks. Bounces a lot. Both very slow and fast tanks.
Big alpha damage. Slow reload. Low accuracy and long aim time.
Germany. Traditional tanks. Decent speed. Has a lot of view range.
Good reload compared to the damage output. High accuracy.
U.S.A. High armor values on turrets. Decent speed on all tanks. Top tiers
focus on lower alpha, but faster reload speed. Turret Tank Destroyers.
French. No armor whatsoever on any tanks in the entire tech tree. Except for a few low tiers. Higher tiers get magazines in their
guns, being able to fire 6 shots in little over 12 seconds. Great flankers. Almost all of them are very very fast.
Of course all of these nations have exceptions, which I will cover for you in a later episode.
With this information
I hope that you know which way you want to go for now. You can always change your mind.
But lets get back to what you have right now.
Right now you have 4 pieces of metal with a gun strapped onto them. Before you
press the mighty red BATTLE button up top, lets look around the garage first.
Top right you'll see Buy Premium, Get Gold, Exchange Gold and Convert Experience.
We'll get into these later, since you
won't have to use either to get past the first few tiers in a matter of hours.
Underneath Convert Experience is the Research button. Click
it to bring up your research tree.
Here you will be able to pick upgrades for your tank. As you can see these are very cheap at lower tiers, but as you progress through
the game these will go all the way up to 60.000 xp to unlock a better gun or engine.
But don't worry about that for now.
When you upgrade a module, like I just upgraded the tracks, close down your Research window
and go down beneath your tank. Here you'll see modules which you have equipped already.
I just upgraded new tracks, so I'll click on the tracks and click on the new track without
the green color.
This will equip the new tracks and I'll now be able to turn faster.
ALWAYS remember to go down here and equip newly researched modules.
Some people forget and
get very angry because they don't feel a difference in the tank.
I've done that myself, but then I get back to the garage
and realise that I forgot to equip the damn thing.
Top left side you'll see your crew.
Right now you'll see a 50% crew, as they progress towards the 100% all of
your stats will change. You'll have faster acceleration, you'll reload faster, you'll have better accuracy, greater view and other stuff.
When you reach the 100% mark you'll also get to choose a skill/perk, but that's pretty
far off in the future for you, so we'll save that for another episode.
Right now underneath your tank you'll see Service and Exterior.
Click on Service
and you'll be met by this screen.
From the top
Repairs, Ammunition, Consumables
Right now you might as well click on Repair Automaticly, since you won't be able to drive your tank again, unless you repair
it. The more damage you take in a battle, the more you'll have to pay when you get back to your garage.
So if you're capturing your enemy's base and the rest of the team is hunting the last three tanks and you know
you don't have much credit left, just stay in the base and capture it, instead of risking your repair bill.
BUT this only counts in the lower tiers. When you get up in the higher tiers,
thinking about your repair bill in a battle, where people need YOUR help to win.
You should not be selfish enough to think about the credits you
might lose, when going to help them out.
Got that, soldier?
Ammunition should also be ticked off at Resupply Automaticly, since you don't want to get into a game without shells
to fire. I've done that a few times, silly thing.
As you can see there are different kinds of shells.
There are AP shells, Armor Piercing
HEAT, High Explosive Anti Tank
shells and then there's HE, High Explosive shells.
The Heat shells cost you gold as you can see over here. These
aren't worth buying if you know where to hit your enemy.
They will give you better penetration and nothing else, but if you don't know where you can penetrate
your enemy, then those gold shells are going to bounce, just as easy as any AP shell.
A later episode will show you where to penetrate
any tank at your tier and +2/-2 tiers.
HE shells are used, when you can't penetrate a tank normally. The shell will hit your enemy and explode on
the outside of the tank, sometimes killing a crew member inside.
So bring a few of those with you.
Then we have Consumables. These are 3000 credits each and you shouldn't put these on low tiers, since you won't earn any credits
if you use one or 2 of these in a battle, where you only earn 10.000 credits, that's a high number,
but use 2 consumables and you've already used 6.000 credits
of those, then come repair bill and ammo cost.
In a future episode I'll speak about all of the consumables, but for now, there's no need for you to equip
any of them, since if you get hit in the gun, you're highly likely dead within a few seconds.
BUT when you seem to have earned a lot of credits, then you can start
adding them to any of your tanks, but for now, leave them be.
Exterior is just a way to shine up your tank. This will cost credits or gold, but only the gold camos will
stay forever. I would advice you to not waste any credits on these, but that's up to you of course.
Underneath your Service button there's another bar with 3 equipment slots.
As you can see, these are
VERY expensive, but on the later tiers, you'll want to equip a few of these.
Especially the Gun Rammer, which isn't right here, but on future tanks it will be
available. This will increase your loading speed by 10%, which is pretty good.
The equipment will also be covered in a future episode, where I talk about all of the equipment
and for which tank they should be used on. But for now, just forgot about them.
All the way at the bottom you'll see Channels, Contacts, General, Tank
Companies and to the right there are two nameless buttons.
First one with a speechbubble is invites. When someone invites you to a platoon or company battle, a
link will pop up asking you to click it. Click it and you'll be in the platoon/company.
The other nameless button is your battle history for the games you've played today.
All of the battle information will be
down there and you'll be able to scroll through all the battles and see what you earned in each.
In channels you'll find other people who've made channel groups, where they speak
to each other. You can create your own channel as well.
Contacts houses all your contacts and you can also search for contacts here.
To add anyone to your contacts,
just search for their name and then right click on it and Add to Friend List.
General is the general chat and you can speak to anyone online here.
Companies is the place where people can join a company, you too by just double clicking on any company that isn't private,
then you'll have to pick a tank and press ready, then the company leader will start the battle and you're off.
That's it for this episode guys.
Next episode we'll take our first ride in a tank
and I'll show you all of the in-game UI and how everything works.
Take care and I'll see you next time!