Analyse your team
Is this mixture of tanks likely to defend or push?
Will they all just find a bush or will they help...
Uuhh look at that long cannon :D
Wait what? Oh right, analysing the team
Most of our team consist of big mediums
So helping by scouting on one side probably
won't be a bad idea
Make sure that someone is going your way
If not, then who will hurt the ones you scout?
Circle a few times, while they get into gear
Type 59 and VK3601(H)
Decent enough
30 seconds into the match
If their scouts would have gone on a suicide
rush, we would have seen them by now
Or I shall find them waiting in a bush up ahead
Keep low.
Stay on the path.
Get a lot closer before breaking cover
If you meet someone, the rocks on the path
will provide excellent cover
First tank spotted.
Don't engage!
You're a spotter first!
A fighter later.
Stay alive!
Nothing's worse than a wasted scout
The first hit.
Don't panic!
Panic leads to mistakes
Most people would go left and go
straight for arty
But look at the minimap
They're all in defensive positions.
Proceed to the right
We JUST dodged a shot from their
biggest tank destroyer.
Do NOT push your luck!
Pull back and let the situation unfold
An enemy Type 59 is zoned in on our teammate
When you can easily tell that your
opponent is blinded by bloodlust,
that is the perfect moment to strike!
Don't get too greedy
We just got him 4 times + setting him on fire.
Time to retreat for now.
Also his mates are coming on the left
Never forget your latest intel
We scouted that ISU ourselves and he's still there
Quickly take a zoomed in peek to see what he's up to
When the coast is clear, move along
Know your map locations
We could easily sit here safely and take shots on
the Löwe, since the ISU couldn't get out of his
cover without putting himself into a dangerous position
Know the weakness of your enemy
Breaking cover with a sharp turn is something
the ISU's accuracy doesn't like
Also you'd already be halfway across the entrance
when spotted by him
Use your third person view to your advantage
Spot an opening and roll out!
Make your enemy completely helpless
Never straight towards an enemy!
Turn at the first opportunity you get!
The guessing game
You can go left or you can go right
He can stay put or he can turn around to face you
Always be at the other end of the cannon!
No matter what tier tank
The only time you're allowed
to go straight at an enemy
When you know that he has JUST fired
and his reload time is long
The only reason I went for this shot was?
That's right, friends!
The Tiger just fired upon me seconds ago
and is now reloading
Know your limits!
Here I knew that I could take a shot from the tiger
and still live
From here it's simply go for the artillery
Don't believe everything you read
"we have the worst arty ever seen"
Rewind the video and watch how our artillery
hits their Löwe and nearly kills it
by setting it on fire and doing direct damage
Wait did it just say Base Captured?!
"Confederate"
"Scout"
Thank you for watching!
I really hope you enjoyed this video
and had a fun time learning
More videos with running tips coming soon!
I like this tune. \o/