This first match will focus on the KV-2 as a camping sniper.
The KV-2 will do fairly good amounts of damage, even when not fully penetrating.
That's why it's a good idea to keep back and play the supporting role,
as you won't survive more than 3 shots from any big tanks.
Avoid getting into the view range of your enemies, instead get inside their mind.
A KV-2 derp shot will most likely do a lot of damage, destroy a module
or kill a crew member. Example coming later in the video!
But I now see what all others have been trying to tell me, in the comments
section and therefore I decided on making this Tips video,
since the KV-2 was very requested.
This is taking too long, speeding up the clip!
First thing about the KV-2. The aimtime.
At 4 seconds it's the slowest aiming tank.
Next up is the reload speed. Clocked in at 2,5 shots per minute.
This means 24 seconds reload time. Can be reduced by Gun Rammer, Vent
and BiA (Brothers in Arms perk)
So take your time aiming and if the shot doesn't seem to be there,
hold back and wait for a better opportunity!
This KV-3 is open and should receive a gift from me, no matter what!
No crew confirmation, so I missed.
This will happen a lot. Get used to it.
While waiting for your massive reload time to pass, find better cover in a bush,
so that the camo can work for you.
The range indicator at the top of my crosshair tells me that none of these tanks
can see me.
The best view range is on the KV-5 and that one stops at 350.
This is just something I know from playing the game A LOT, so don't think too much
about this, until you start caring about such things.
Range indicator can be found in the same crosshair mod,
which is in Locastan's Mod Pack.
Several targets appeared.
Find the most important.
Here's my list of priorities.
1. Tanks which can spot you(scouts)
2. Nearly dead targets(1-200 hp)
3. Full HP tanks to give them a shock
Full HP tanks taking damage always think about showing their face twice.
Slowly lead your target(to not lose aimtime) and when you're comfortable
with the shot, send it flying!
If I had had the Sixth Sense perk, I would've known that I was spotted,
but instead a lucky bounce lets me know that my camo is broken.
Time to back up a little.
Range indicator from before, lets me know that I'm outside their view range.
Letting me relax, since I'm no longer spotted by the dead scout.
With a very close to death KV-3 I tried my luck, but if I had waited a second more,
I could've had a much better shot at him.
But with the derp gun, you can afford taking these shots, since you could
potentially hurt someone with those derp shells.
Since the KV-5 and KV-4 was so close to eachother I could've hurt them both,
but the KV-4 was bouncy on the side of his turret, so only got a "That was close!"
But this is basicly what the KV-2 is good at.
Supporting with constant damage shells.
No matter the penetration.
With more cover and better Matchmaking, I could've easily been up at the frontlines,
fighting against the biggest tanks. "Most" high tiers respect a KV-2 with
the derp gun, since the damage roll is so random.
The enemy is flanking and priority shifts to defending the flank.
The US M103 has less armor in the front and is therefore my target.
Again lead your target, wait to see if he decides to stop for a moment to aim.
Even though my aim wasn't the best in the world the shell went to the left
and hit him for a whopping 823 damage.
There's an E-75 on the loose.
Listen to your crew and get going!
NEVER take such a shot!
The Tiger is way too close to the IS-3 and hitting our ally would make us lose
the frontline. Wait for a better opportunity!
The Tiger has moved into the open! Now is the chance to take him out!
Remember to lead your target! Anticipate his movement!
By looking at him several times, while my aim was getting to its smallest size,
I noticed that he started turning.
Therefore I waited for him to be driving away from me, giving me the perfect shot!
E-75 spotted, but also a SU-100 going for our IS-3.
Turning around to anticipate his movement and get off a shot,
before moving towards the E-75!
My shell flies straight across his head and all I can do from now on is move
my big butt. The reload on the SU-100 is much faster. Close to double as fast
and his aimtime is 2,9. Only a second faster, but I can't fight 1v1 with him.
He misses and I can now focus on helping our Löwe with taking down the E-75.
The Löwe gets another good shot in on him and his fate is now in my hands.
Miss and die or hit and even the battle!
The Löwe gets taken out and it's now me against a SU-100 hiding/capping and
a SU-14 artillery. Bad odds...
The capcounter in Encounter mode is A LOT slower than regular capping.
So I have plenty of time to drive around and get him from the side.
The SU-14 appears and it's a battle between 0,6 vs 0,55 accuracy and
4 vs 6,9 aimtime
He goes for the lucky accuracy roll and gets me.
Nothing I could do about that.
I still managed to get close to 1000 xp for a loss, just for hurting tanks from
a distance. Onward to the next clip!
Here we are in my favorite environment in the KV-2. A city map.
Artillery neutralized and we can play peek a boo!
Right there I actually thought my platoon mate was fighting against the IS in D2.
Clearly not and totally my own mistake!
Could've/Should've tried to hit that guy.
He's trying to flank us and is totally open!
I think I was going "just get away!" at the time.
Don't always rush to the next corner.
Take a look at what's going on and decide what's best for your team.
I was thinking "lets go help against the IS!" but next time I look at him,
he's on fire and has lost more than half his health, so I decide not to go help.
If the enemy were to peek around the corner, I would be the first target they spot.
Always stay closest to the building your enemy is closest to.
Sometimes you should definitely take the shot, before your aimtime has finished.
The enemy is no matter what getting behind the cover and not coming out again.
So you might aswell try your luck, once in a while!
Your reload isn't even halfway, so there's no reason for you to go up there to
peek out and risk your hp.
Wait for the reload to get a bit closer to done, then go up there :)
If you rewind a bit, you'll hear a lot of cannons being fired, this means they're
quite busy with eachother, so you can easily take a quick peek and
fire a shell into someone's face.
Never peek more than necessary, so gently tap the W key to roll forward very slowly,
until you can see one of them.
As you might've noticed I was aiming for the Tiger P, since he has the toughest armor
The ARL44 can be penetrated by nearly any tank.
So using my big derp shell on him on purpose would not be very helpful to the team.
Oops! Forgot my own rule.
I use a repair kit to fix my tracks, since my reload is nearly done,
so I go out there to give him a little payback!
The Tiger P is retreating, so it's okay to pursue him. But only a little.
Don't rush him. And stay close to the cover on the right as always!
If an enemy hits you, before you get to hit him.
Don't just sit back with a small area of him to shoot at.
Go out there and get a firm shot in his face. Don't do what I'm about to do.
Luckily he fired at someone in the back of E1, so I'm perfectly safe,
while going out there to deal the finishing blow! :D
With your slow aimtime, you might never be able to aim in on newly spotted
artillery, so feel free to fire a shot without the reticle having moved an inch.
Just to try.
At ANY other circumstance, NEVER peek while capping an enemy base.
Especially if you were the first in the capzone.
But in this case, the VK3601(H) is already out in the open and the enemy will
spot him first and most likely aim for him before you.
If the enemy is in our base and we are close to winning on cap,
then I never leave the capzone to go hunt them. It's not worth the trouble
going to the other end of the map.
9 shots = 2155 xp and 46k credits?!
Lets take a look at some different situations and shots in the KV-2.
T20 taking 754 damage to the front
AMX50B taking 772 damage
I was waiting for him for more than 1 minute.
Killing a JagdTiger by constantly firing at his gun!
Totally destroyed his gun(again?)
16 seconds goes by before he retaliates.
I play with Locastan's Mod Pack
A collection of awesome mods
If you need help improving your game,
take a look at Ding760's Tank Academy
Also DezGamez and Maxwell042 both offer great gameplay videos different from mine,
focusing more on Live commentary
Take care :)