Hi guys and welcome to my first commentary on a tanks video
I've been sick for the last two weeks, or not "sick!",
but my throat was very sore
I don't know what kind of  illness I have inflicted upon me
BUT... Now I will try to make a commentary
On Sand River with my T-50-2
I immediately saw that there was a few artillery pieces in the game,
but I decided not to go for them
because I'm much more valuable as a scout,
lighting up targets on the hills and you'll see exactly why
But here this VK2801 is trying to duke it out with me,
but I'm much more mobile than him and his gun is inaccurate or he just
doesn't know how to manually aim like me.
I never auto-aim, because if I'm on the move then the gun is inaccurate
as hell, so I might as well aim myself, instead of letting the computer
say "oh the tank is that way, so I'm just going to shoot that way"
But you can see I'm circling him and my teammates finish him off, and
that's pretty much all she wrote.
Then I proceed to scout the tanks, that's coming up here.
They generally do that, so that's a good place to go, if you wanna be a
spotter on this map.
A Tiger P, I can do nothing against that. He has 200 mm armor in the front
and my gun with 118 mm  penetration can't do anything against that.
A Panther in the city, I decide not to go for it, because his gun has a
very high rate of fire, so I go and fight this KV instead
But I didn't notice the 2 T34s right down there and I notice now and I
just think "Oh my god! Get the hell out of there."
Use the terrain to my advantage, check back to see if they had a
possible shot on me, if they did I would've changed direction, but my
starting direction was good enough
The Panther still down in the city, not gonna fight it, instead going to
help out T34 of our own against this Tiger II.
Annoy the hell out of the driver inside.
by constantly shooting him in the head, as he tries to turn and fight me.
He's not a very good driver, but his name is blurry, so we can't really
see it, so I can say he's not a very good driver without offending anyone
But he starts to turn the other way and he has the Tiger P as backup,
so Woouow that was close.
So I decide to back off, because it's a hopeless situation. You can't
circle kill anyone if they have backup, that's stationary.
If they were moving aswell, then I might've had a chance, but they didn't
Driving in a straight line, away from enemy fire is a very bad idea.
But I only had this T-50 in my mind, so..
You see that acceleration? I'm coming nearly full speed, only slowing down
a little and this T-50 just spurts away from me, he sprints away from me.
It's mad. The acceleration is awesome and I love the T-50, but I need
the topspeed to get away from dangerous situations. And the T-50 just
doesn't have that.
The Hummel is up in the hills, as you can see on the minimap, but he dies
I think he dies... now? Yeah. So that's not a priority, the priority here
is to go help my teammates, the KV-3 and T34, because they're getting
surrounded.
I'm just going to circle this T34, but his turret traverse speed is very
fast and he's looking ahead of me,
so I knew he knew how to fight against the scouts
So I really just had to let the guys around me work for me.
You can see I get free shots, but I don't know where to aim right now
Not from this view. If I zoomed in I could hit him properly.
As you can see, I'm aiming NOW, at the tank, instead of the tracks or
the curvy spots
Uh that was the last tank, so yeah. Title screen, battle stats.
Yeah, I was sniper and scout, fooling around in the hills,
shooting like a mad man. Only missing 5 shots. Decent.
I hope this commentary was done alright.
But the Tips videos will still have the stopping tips with
the jeopardy theme.
We'll see how long that goes.
So thanks for watching!