Hey guys
And welcome to the light tank replay contest results.
I've looked through A LOT of light tank replays and
they were divided into 2 categories.
Tier 5s doing extremely well and tier 1-4 doing nothing spectacular.
I can't blame people for sending in their replays because well it's
a replay contest and higher tiers will always perform better
so as I've said earlier I'm going to do a lower tier replay contest,
in the future
so the smaller guys will have a better chance at winning,
since this was an unlimited tier contest.
There are great replays amongst these, no doubt,
but everyone should have a chance at winning gold
even the guys just starting and in this sort of contest
they wouldn't stand a chance really.
But then again very good tankers could just purchase one of
the smaller tanks and win anyways, with their superior skills.
I even thought about limiting the contest even more to get the
new players involved, as in you'd have to have less than 1000
or 2000 battles on your account to be able to enter
but that would also be overkill in my opinion,
since I shouldn't just exclude everyone from being able to enter.
But the next contest will be a tier 4 highest tier limit for light tanks.
A tier 6 limit on medium tanks and tier 7 limit on heavy tanks.
All of those tanks doesn't require endless grinding to get,
so everyone will have the opporturnity to join in.
Anyways lets move on to the results for the light tanks.
First up we have a quick match, where DukeTT or DukeDoubleT does
a pretty daring move against 3 big enemy tanks.
At first he goes to the bridge over here, to do a little bit of scouting.
And meets noone on the bridge, so he proceeds and he just sits there
and waits for a little while, but nothing shows up in the beginning
but when people start showing up, he decides to cross the bridge and
is met by a Löwe, a T34 and a SU-152.
And instead of stopping he goes straight between them. Right in between
them. Fires in desperation, but he gets past them and they all miss him,
or his tracks soak up all the damage, so he gets past them without taking
any damage at all. Even missing a shot right there.
He then proceeds to kill the Grille in the base.
And after he has done that, he goes down to annoy the SU-152,
which he drove past earlier.
An IS-3 finishes off the kill and then they proceed to cap the base.
That was the third honourable mention and lets move on.
And in this match, we have another T-50-2. This time it's Mugen_FTW and
he drives straight through the middle and scouts all the enemy tanks in
one run, that's 15 tanks in one run. Without dying.
The artillery signals that they are going to kill the enemy artillery,
but the enemy artillery disappears, so he turns around to spot it once
again and he does.
And both artillery press T on it and one of them hit. And that's the
second honourable mention.
Here you see the 15 tanks, if you spot everyone there will be a scrollbar
Because there's no space for the 15th tank. I don't know why they
designed the menu for that, but lets move on to
the first honourable mention.
And in the first honourable mention we have a Chaffee, with Azakow inside
He told his teammates to look for enemy tanks on the east side of the map
and is therefore driving up there to spot the incoming threats.
An AMX 13 75 comes rushes in and Azakow
and his teammates quickly dispatch of it.
Then a couple of Type 59s approach and Azakow takes up the battle,
head to head.
Something the Chaffee is very capable of,
because of it's high penetration and damage output.
One of the type 59 makes a mistake of going straight into the open and
Azakow takes advantages of this to get in a few shots to the side of
the Type 59 and then sends off a shell into the other tracked T-59.
He keeps on shooting at the desperate Type 59 trying to get away,
but he gets taken out!
He then proceeds to help with the last type 59 and then he runs down to
the city, where a T110 is hiding and he kills a KV-3,
just because he can.
Then he rushes out from his cover and takes out the T110 from behind,
while the T110 is focusing on much bigger targets ahead of him.
After the kill he drives into the city where he takes out another
high tier american tank by shooting it in the back,
while it focuses on something bigger in front.
A great first honourable mention in my opinion.
But then we have the winner of the light tank replay contest and it is
ViktorKitov.
Yet again another T-50-2, but was a very popular tank in this class.
He goes spotting at first, slowly but steady going down the middle,
he then decides to run into a rock, very clever tactic, but after that
he decides to lure a KV-3 into a spot,
where it has to chance of escaping from a circle kill
but I think Viktor takes the whole circle thing a bit too serious,
since he completes the circle, outrunning the traverse speed on the
KV-3's turret and passes it,
luckily not being hit by the shot fired from the KV-3.
After the KV-3 has been injured,
Viktor decides on the hitting a rock tactic again.
He then decides to go help take out the KV-3,
before running towards the enemy base again.
On the way to the enemy base a KV-2 appears,
which Viktor also helps take out.
He gets a shot in the back of his turret and his gun gets destroyed.
So he decides to run away for now.
While running around on the map, he notice the french tank from earlier
trying to sneak into his base, so he goes to deal with it.
The french tank tracks Viktor and then he starts reversing towards Viktor
The french tank should've kept moving away from him, to put more distance
between Viktor and him, because the closer Viktor is to the french tank,
the further the french gun has to turn to be able
to keep up with Viktor's speed.
Viktor hits a T30 on the move, while moving towards the enemy base and
then proceeds to hit a T34 in the butt.
And these are the last shots Viktor is going to fire,
because the game ends right after this.
Viktor wins this class because it's a perfect example of how a game with
no kills at all can earn you a lot of xp, so instead on focusing on
getting that last hit on a tank.
Start thinking about damaging as many tanks as you possible in on game.
People are too focused on getting Top Guns and Boelter's Medals.
They forget that you don't have to get any kills in any games to have a
much higher average xp, than the guy with 5 kills each game.
So that's why I picked Viktor to win!
Hope you enjoyed the video and heavy are coming really soon!