Learn how to take down heavy tanks
With the smallest tanks
Learn the basics to rule the battlefield
with the heavy tanks
Learn the difference between useless suicide
and being helful to your team
The T49
Bottom of the foodchain, again?!
Analyse your team
Oh great, bottom tank again
Familiar theme in this tank
So what's the best way to hel out our team?
Well this tank has one thing going for it and that's speed
Lets go to a very good spotting bush and help our team
by lighting up the enemy team while they advance.
And then we'll decide what to do from there
Been a while since we last did this, but never forget.
Only exception is if you're in heavy tank and spawned at
the edge of your base.
We're going to that bush, just so you know.
It's perfect spotting bush, unless the enemy has a fast
tank sitting here and sots you as you move up there
From this bush we'll be able to cover this area
Dang it, we're spotted.. Nothing else to do, but move back
and fourth, while shooting at him.
Stopping once in a while to get a more precise shot
Keeping your crosshair on the enemy, even if you're not firing,
just to see when it's safe to move away from this trapped position.
With an AMX12t and an IS pushing, we should push along
and help them by causing a distraction
A T25 AT appears! He could one-shot the T49 if he
got a high damage roll, so keep driving past him
Continue to his rear and stop him from retreating
in any possible way
As you just saw the T49 has an absolutely horrible
traverse speed.
Remember that to know wich situations you're able to
deal with. This will come into play later as well.
Keep following his rear whereever he goes
to take away any possible way of turning
In most situations you should move after a kill, since
the artillery will still have visual of you for a few
seconds, so he could take a lucky shot and possibly hit you.
An IS-3 and heavily damaged VK3601 popped up. In most situations
you shouldn't go up against tier 8s in a tier 5, but since
we're the smallest and fastest tank on our team, let's flank him.
Oh and take out any potential targets on the way.
The IS-3 just fired, so it's time to use his reload time
against him, so get in close
What was that?
This is NOT me just fooling around. THIS is how large the
traverse circle is, when driving at full speed.
Luckily I'm heading straight for that wreck over there,
so let's hide behind it and play peek a boo with him
We're trapped here, so keep going back and forth to keep
him guessing where we'll go
The penetration on the T49 is high enough to penetrate
IS-3 from the side
Keep doing this back and forth untill help can arrive.
We've got a powerful TD coming to help us.
And even if we didn't get help, we'd be annoying
one of the biggest tanks on the enemy team :D
Ouch, better get out of the way, now that the Is-3 has
been dealt with
The rest of the enemies are definitely hiding inside the
forest, so find a decent house to snipe from, when the bigger and more durable tanks advance.
The PzIV was spotted first, so our allies are highly
likely aiming at him first, so shoot once and move onto the next target.
Only big tanks left, so if we want more xp and credits
we have to move in on them
When people are close to dying, they tend to want to have
a final kill to make the loss a little less painful
And you'll see this IS-3 do that and since I had to get
out of the way from it, I unfortunately get hit by a Sherman ally, but that stuff happens.
Thank you for watching
Hope you enjoyed learning that, just because you're at
the bottom of the foodchain, it doesyn't make you useless at all :)
I've been getting a lot of comments on map tactics So I'll
start a series focusing on diffrent tactics for every map
It's going to be a mixture of in-game footage and HP maps
with outlines of routes and flanking possibilities, etc.
Unless you want something else, then please let me know in
the comments.